All right. Let's head out.
好 走吧
If you're going to Kawane,
要去川根的话
bring back some Kawane tea.
记得帮我买川根茶回来哦
Mum hasn't been as worried about me travelling lately.
最近好像没那么担心我了呢
Has she gotten used to it?
是习惯了吗
But
不过
Grandpa did say that you're most prone to making mistakes
爷爷说过 开始习惯的时候
when you get comfortable.
才是最危险的时期
I should keep my guard up.
还是保持着适度的紧张感吧
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 3: BRIDGE COUNTRY
(第3话 前往吊桥之国)
It's 3.30 AM.
现在是3点半
"KAWANE RYOGOKU" I'm supposed to meet Aya
(川根两国) 和小绫是约好8点在千头站会合
That should give me about 4.5 hours.
有4个半小时应该绰绰有余吧
We'll decide
会合之后…
where to go after we meet up.
再和小绫讨论要去哪里吧
"ABT-ICHISHIRO STATION" As for Nadeshiko,
(ABT市代站) 和抚子则是直接约在露营场会合
But is she really okay getting there alone?
不过她一个人真的没问题吗
Morning, Rin.
凛 早安
You're up early.
你还真早起呢
Heard you're heading full throttle to the hidden gem of Ikawa
听说你今天要和抚子老家 那边的朋友
with Nadeshiko's friend from her hometown today.
马力全开地骑去井川的秘境呀?
What era are you living in?
那是哪个年代的用词啊
Speaking of Ikawa,
说到井川
it's known for Kawane tea, hot springs, and the suspension bridge, right?
那边的川根茶和温泉 以及吊桥好像很有名哦
I think so.
好像是
Also, there's that Kawane tea soft serve they sell in front of Senzu Station.
还有千头站前面卖的川根茶冰淇淋
Heard it's a bit bitter, but supposedly delicious.
听说吃起来有点苦苦的 似乎很美味哦
Is that so?
这样啊
Remember to get me one.
记得帮我买一支回来哦
By the time I get back to Minobu, it'll be soup.
等我回到身延 冰早就融化了啦
Goodness! Can't believe you won't buy it for me!
天哪 居然不帮人家买
Unacceptable!
真是太过分了
-Unacceptable!
-真是太过分了
You two are up bright and early too, huh?
你们两个也够早起的啊
It's starting to get light.
天色开始变亮了
It's cold,
虽然很冷
but it's nice to see
但这种太阳渐渐升起的感觉
the sun rising.
真不错呢
"SUMATAKYO" Mountain road from here on out, huh?
(寸又峡) 接下来要开始走山路了吗
This is tough!
好难骑
It's been nothing but hairpin turns!
一直遇到发夹弯
Why do I keep
我怎么好像
getting these road conditions?
常常遇到这种路啊
HAMAMATSU
(滨松)
ONE-MAN
(单人乘务)
Let's see...
我看看哦
At Shizuoka Station, change to the train bound for Hamamatsu Station.
在静冈站转乘往滨松站的列车
From Kanaya Station,
搭到金谷站后
"ABT-ICHISHIRO STATION" transfer to the Oigawa Railway
(ABT市代站) 再转搭大井川铁道到千头站
It's a long ride.
要搭好久啊
Gotta be careful not to forget about the transfer.
得小心别忘记转车才行
Glad I didn't forget it.
太好了 没有忘记
I've been to Oigawa before.
大井川的话 我之前有去过呢
Really? Was it fun?
真的吗 好玩吗
I went to the hot springs in Sumatakyo.
我在寸又峡泡了温泉
It was nice.
还满舒服的哦
I went during maple leaf season.
不过当时是枫叶季
There were so many people on the suspension bridge
吊桥上的人多到我差点被挤扁
Is it that bad?
这么多人吗
Well, the cherry blossoms aren't in bloom yet.
但现在樱花也还没开
It probably won't be that crowded.
应该没什么人吧
Thank goodness.
太好了
Besides hot springs,
除了温泉之外
there's also a foot bath cafe…
还有一间足汤咖啡…
Hold up, Sakura.
姐姐 等一下
I want to be surprised when I get there,
我想把这份感动保留到露营的时候
so no spoilers please.
所以你剧透到这里就好
-I can't hear you... -Hot spring. Foot bath.
-我听不到 -足汤温泉
-Wasabi soba.
-芥末荞麦面
By the way, what's that?
话说回来 那是什么?
Oh, this?
这个吗
"TRAVEL EGG CASE" It's an egg case.
(便携式鸡蛋盒) 这是鸡蛋盒哦
I'm planning to make Omurice for dinner.
因为我打算煮蛋包饭当晚餐
I bought this to carry the eggs.
为了把鸡蛋带过去 刚才特地去买的
Omurice doesn't sound
露营吃蛋包饭什么的
very camp-like.
感觉不是很搭呢
Actually, it's because Aya said
其实是因为小绫说要帮我 从滨松买汉堡排过去啦
Hamburg steak?
汉堡排?
That hamburg steak?
那个汉堡排啊
That's right. That hamburg steak.
没错…就是那个汉堡排
It's not everyday we get to have that,
毕竟机会难得 我才想说煮个西式晚餐
Now that you mention it, we haven't had that hamburg steak
这么说起来 自从搬到山梨后
since we moved to Yamanashi.
就很久没吃过那个汉堡排了呢
Reached Senzu.
到千头了
SENZU STATION
(千头站)
SENZU HOT SPRINGS
(千头温泉)
SAKURAGI RELIGIOUS SUPPLIES STORE
(樱木佛具店)
Aya isn't here yet.
小绫好像还没到呢
TAXI STAND
(乘车站)
Brr, it's cold.
好冷
"KAWANEHONCHO, SHIZUOKA" It's warm at noon.
(静冈县川根本町 最低气温3度) 中午虽然很暖和
But the temperature in the morning and evening is colder than
但早晚的温度 好像比伊豆露营时还冷呢
Nadeshiko is taking the train to the campsite.
抚子是搭电车到露营场
A nice, slow ride.
慢悠悠地搭电车过去
Leisurely, relaxing,
感觉很惬意 应该也挺不错的
and she won't be tired.
而且还不会累
There she comes.
来了…
Rin!
小凛
Long time no…
好久不…
ALL BEAT UP
(遍体鳞伤)
SENZU STATION
(千头站)
Better?
好多了吗
Much better.
好多了
Didn't expect just riding straight here would be so brutal.
没想到只是直直骑过来 也会这么要命
And the winds on National Route 1 are so strong.
而且国一那边的风超大
And those big trucks passing by are terrifying.
还有大型卡车会经过 有够可怕的
I get it.
我懂
Just riding a 100cc motorbike is exhausting enough.
光是骑100cc的机车 就已经这么累了
You, Rin, who rode a 50cc to Izu, must be a maniac.
骑50cc去伊豆的小凛 肯定是变态呢
Hey, that's going too far.
你也说得太过分了吧
We arrived way too early.
我们来得实在太早了
None of the shops in front of the station are open yet.
站前的店都还没开呢
Heard the Kawane tea soft serve at that shop is good.
听说那间店的川根茶冰淇淋 很好吃哦
Speaking of which,
这么说起来
my parents asked me to buy some Kawane tea.
我爸妈还叫我买川根茶回去呢
Same here.
我家也是
Let's swing by tomorrow before heading home to buy some.
那就明天回家前绕过去买吧
Sounds good.
好啊
Did you bring all the gear over?
你有带装备过来吗
Pretty much everything.
基本上都带来了
Tents and sleeping bags really take up space.
帐篷和睡袋真的很占位子呢
I also brought the famous hamburg steak from Hamamatsu.
我还带了滨松很有名的那个汉堡排
Look forward to it.
敬请期待吧
I've prepped the ingredients
我的炖牛肉
for my beef stew too.
也事先备好料带过来了
Can't wait!
好期待哦
But the hamburg steaks are raw, aren't they?
不过汉堡排是生鲜制品的吧
Won't it go bad if it's kept in the bag for so long?
一直放在包包里不会坏掉吗
I froze it solid beforehand and then put it in the cooler bag.
我事先把它冰得硬梆梆的 才放进保冷袋里
By evening, it should be thawed out.
到傍晚时 应该就差不多解冻了
I see.
原来如此
To make dinner even tastier,
为了让晚餐变得更美味
let's skip lunch.
中午就别吃了
After all, an empty stomach is the best seasoning, right?
毕竟空腹就是最棒的调味料呀
All right, then...
那么 差不多…
Time to set off.
该出发了吧
Let's go.
出发吧
Wait.
等等
We haven't even decided where to go yet.
我们根本还没决定要去哪里吧
Let's just wander around and ride until we reach Lake Hatanagi.
就到处走走逛逛 骑到畑薙湖为止吧
Lake Hatanagi,
畑薙湖
the deepest lake accessible by drive
是大井川上的众多水坝湖当中
among the many dam lakes on Oigawa.
可用私家车抵达的最深处的湖泊
The regional road 60 leads straight to Lake Hatanagi.
由于一路直通到畑薙湖的县道60号
Not only is the road surface uneven, but it's also very rugged.
不仅路面不平 而且非常崎岖
Hence, it's also known as the "danger road."
因此也被称之为"险道"
Are you serious?
你认真的吗
Didn't you just collapse from exhaustion earlier?
刚才不是都累到趴下来了吗
And now we're riding into the "danger road"...
居然还要骑"险道"
After a little rest, I'm fine now.
稍微休息过后 现在已经没事了啦
Okay, let's go...
好了 走吧…
Are you sure you're okay?
真的没问题吗
The Oigawa Basin.
大井川流域
Known as "the land of suspension bridges."
那里被称之为"吊桥胜地"
"RYOGOKU NO TSURIBASHI" Not only are there small bridges
(两国吊桥) 不仅有林业用的小桥
but also sturdy bridges that can be driven across.
还有足以开车经过的坚固大桥
There are countless suspension bridges throughout the entire Oigawa basin.
整个大井川流域的吊桥 可说是数不胜数
There are even more suspension bridges than I thought.
吊桥的数量比想象中还多呢
Although the "Dream Suspension Bridge" in Sumatakyo is the most famous,
虽然寸又峡的"梦之吊桥" 是最有名的
there are others that look pretty interesting too.
不过也有其他不错的吊桥哦
Like this one.
像这里
Seems we can ride our bikes up there.
好像就能把机车骑上去
It's normal to see bikers taking photos and uploading them to social media.
所以经常看到骑士们 拍照上传到社群网站上呢
Yo!
嗨
So, Rin,
所以啊 小凛
on the way to Lake Hatanagi,
去畑薙湖的路上
let's make a detour whenever we see a suspension bridge.
只要有看到吊桥就绕过去看看吧
A suspension bridge tour, huh?
吊桥巡礼吗
Sounds interesting.
那样感觉也挺有趣的呢
Huh?
什么
What is it?
怎么了吗
I see our next suspension bridge.
我看到下一个吊桥了
Already?
这么快?
Look. It's right over there.
你看 就在那里
Two steel cables hanging on that main pillar.
那根支柱上挂着两根钢索
You're right.
真的耶
I'm impressed you noticed that.
真亏你能看见呢
Another suspension bridge just a few steps away.
才短短几步路就又有一座吊桥 不愧是吊桥胜地呢
It's just an ordinary utility pole.
只是普通的电线杆
"KOYAMA SUSPENSION BRIDGE" Koyama Suspension Bridge.
(小山吊桥) 小山吊桥
This feels even more like a residential area road
这里比刚才的两国吊桥 还更有生活化道路的感觉呢
Yeah.
是啊
The scenery is really nice.
景色真不错
Must be even more beautiful during the maple leaf season.
枫叶季的时候 应该会更漂亮吧
Bet this place will be packed with crowds when that season rolls around.
不过一到枫叶季 这里好像就会变得人挤人哦
After all, this area is famous.
毕竟这一带很有名啊
That's true.
说得也是呢
Better to come during the quieter off-season
与其在闹哄哄的旺季来
than during the bustling peak season.
还是空荡荡的淡季比较好吧
"COLOUR CORRECTION" And just adjust the filter
(颜色调整) 然后再像这样
with your imagination to the desired maple leaf colour.
用想象力调成枫叶的颜色
That's real convenient.
真方便啊
Are we blocking their path?
我们挡到它们的路了吗
They're not people-shy at all.
一点都不怕人呢
Are they a parent and child?
是亲子吗
Looks like this is a wildlife trail too.
看来这里也是 野生动物们的生活道路呢
Looks like it.
好像是这样呢
"OKUSHIZU-OIGAWA LINE, KANAYA STATION" Transfer…
(奥静大井川线金谷站) 转车…
"TICKET COUNTER, KAWANE HOT SPRINGS COUPON" One Okushizu Round-Trip Pass, please.
(售票口 川根温泉优惠券) 请给我一张奥静周游券
That will be 4,900 yen.
总共4900圆
Is this the train to Senzu?
往千头的车是这班吗
This train's got a real retro feel to it.
感觉这台电车还挺复古的呢
Supposedly, you can see Oigawa on both sides of the windows.
听说两侧的窗户都看得到大井川
Okay. Let's go with this side then.
好 那就选这边吧
The seats are soft.
坐垫好软哦
Shaky...
摇摇晃晃的
We're doing a suspension bridge tour.
我们等等会一边进行吊桥巡礼
We'll be heading deep into Oigawa.
一边往大井川深处走
We'll arrive at the campsite in the evening.
傍晚就会到露营场了
Until then, feel free to wander around on your own.
在那之前你先自己随意逛逛吧
I'm on the train from Kanaya to Senzu.
我现在正要从金谷搭往千头
Drive safely. Be there before dinner.
你们骑车小心点 记得在晚餐前回来哦
Got it.
好
They won't be there until evening.
她们要到傍晚才会过来吗
I guess I'll make the most of my solo trip too.
那我也去享受一下 悠哉独旅的感觉吧
LAKE SESSO
(接岨湖)
Lake Sesso.
接岨湖
PARKING, SESSO PARK, TOILET
(停车场 接岨公园 厕所)
This parking lot is huge.
好大的停车场
This suspension bridge looks like a big one.
这次的吊桥好像很大一座呢
Oigawa's suspension bridges are really sturdy.
不觉得大井川的吊桥都很牢固
They barely shake.
基本上不怎么会晃吗
We're just getting started.
好戏接下来才刚要开始哦
EIGHT BRIDGES ROMANTIC ROAD SESSO SUSPENSION BRIDGE (5-MINUTE WALK)
(八桥小道浪漫道路) (往接岨峡大吊桥方向 徒步5分钟)
What's so romantic about this place?
到底哪里浪漫了啊?
Beats me.
根本没什么好浪漫的吧
That grassland is perfect for camping.
这片草地也太适合露营了吧
Is that what caught your attention?
你注意的点是那个吗
"SESSO SUSPENSION BRIDGE" That's a big bridge.
(接岨大吊桥) 这座桥还真大呢
It's huge.
好大哦
And it looks new.
而且感觉还挺新的
Aya.
小绫
"EIGHT BRIDGES SCENIC TRAIL MAP" After crossing this bridge,
(八桥小道散步地图) 过了这座桥后
there are many smaller bridges up ahead.
好像还有很多小桥哦
Says here are eight in total.
说是有八座呢
It'll take a while,
虽然可能会花一点时间
but should we take a look?
要顺便去那边看看吗
Sure. We're here, after all.
当然要 毕竟都来了啊
It's not swaying at all.
一点都不晃呢
It's a big bridge after all.
毕竟这座桥很大嘛
The sides of the bridge have been made transparent.
不过 刻意把两侧的桥面做成透明的
Maybe it's an ode to the suspension bridge it replaced.
或许是在致敬以前的吊桥吧
EIGHT BRIDGES ROMANTIC TRAIL MINAMI-ALPS BIOSPHERE RESERVE
(八桥小道浪漫道路) (南阿尔卑斯山生物保护区)
Please, there's nothing romantic about this.
根本没什么好浪漫的吧
Not at all.
果然一点都不浪漫呢
EIGHT BRIDGES
(八桥)
I… I wasn't trying to make a pun! (Note: "not at all" and "eight bridges")
刚…刚才那个不是刻意在玩梗啦
FIRST BRIDGE: TOCHINOKI BRIDGE
(第一座桥 栃木桥)
It's a mini suspension bridge.
是迷你吊桥耶
SECOND BRIDGE: SAKURA BRIDGE
(第二座桥 樱桥)
This part of the bridge is wet. Be careful. It might be slippery.
这边的桥面有点湿 可能会比较滑
Maybe it rained yesterday.
也许这附近昨天有下雨吧
THIRD BRIDGE: MIZUNARA BRIDGE
(第三座桥 水楢桥)
FLOODED
(淹水)
This is completely soaked through.
这座完全湿透了
It's practically flooded.
根本都积水了嘛
What should we do?
怎么办?
FORCING THEIR WAY THROUGH
(强行突破)
FOURTH BRIDGE: TSUBAKI BRIDGE
(第四座桥 椿桥)
Kanzanji has a bridge like this too, right?
馆山寺也有这种桥吧
Oh, you mean Shibuki Bridge.
你是说水花桥吧
FIFTH BRIDGE: KUWANOKI BRIDGE
(第五座桥 桑木桥)
All these bridges are named after trees.
这些桥都是用树来命名的呢
Now that you mention it, yeah.
这么一说 好像是呢
You think they're named after the trees they're made of?
会不会是以建桥用的木材 来命名的啊?
Not sure about that.
那可不一定
These kind of bridges are usually named after some myth or legend.
这种桥很多都是根据神话 或传说来命名的哦
"SIXTH BRIDGE: MIYAZAWA BRIDGE" Miyazawa…
(第六座桥 宫泽桥) 宫泽…
That's not the name of a tree, isn't it?
这应该不是树的名字吧
What on earth is that? That looks insane!
这是怎样 看起来好危险
Looks like a slide.
长得好像溜滑梯
What if you slip on this slippery bridge?
要是在这种湿答答的桥上跌倒
You'd slide right over to the other end!
搞不好会直接滑到对面去呢
Sounds fun.
感觉很好玩
I'll go first.
那我先走咯
Wait! If you go that fast…
走这么快的话…
Huh?
咦
These are just ordinary steps.
原来是楼梯啊
Aw.
什么嘛
It's just the angle that makes it look like it's flat.
原来只是因为角度的关系 才会看起来像平的啊
What a let-down.
好失望
There, there…
别沮丧…
"SEVENTH BRIDGE: INUKAERI BRIDGE" I have no idea
(第七座桥 狗返桥) 已经搞不懂这些桥的命名标准了
Same.
就是说啊
We finished all of them!
全都走完啦
That was a bridge full course.
简直是游桥全餐呢
Eight in one go was a tad bit much.
一次吃八道大餐 实在是有点饱呢
Eh?
咦
Didn't we only pass seven?
我们是不是只走了七座桥?
SENZU STATION
(千头站)
I'm in Senzu.
到千头了
Transfer here.
接着要在这里转车
Let's see. It's 10:16 AM.
我看看哦 现在是10点16分
"DIRECTION, DEPARTURE TIME" Only three minutes
(方向 发车时间) 离发车只剩3分钟了吗
Guess I'll take the next train.
那就搭下一班
I'll hang around until then.
在那之前先在这附近逛逛吧
Plus, I only had a sandwich today. My stomach's growling.
而且今天我只吃了三明治 肚子都快饿扁了
Should I get an ekiben (train bento) or get some food at a restaurant?
要买铁路便当吃 还是去附近的店家吃呢
NAKAMARU SENZU EKIMAE NAGASHIMA DAM CURRY
(NAKAMARU千头站前 长岛水坝咖喱饭)
It's dam curry!
是水坝咖喱饭
This is a special type of curry
这是一种用白饭模拟水坝
that can only be found in restaurants around dam areas,
再用咖喱酱模拟水坝湖
where white rice is shaped like a dam, and curry represents the lake.
唯有在水坝周边地区的餐饮店 才吃得到的特色咖喱
Because the shape of the rice varies depending on the local dam,
因为白饭会根据当地的水坝 改变造型
dam curry comes in various forms.
所以水坝咖喱饭的模样也很多元
I've been wanting to try dam curry for a while now.
我早就想吃吃看水坝咖喱饭了
Didn't expect to find it here.
没想到会在这种地方遇到它
Oh, that's right. Oigawa is the largest river in Shizuoka.
对了 大井川是静冈县最大的河川
It's a major river, so it makes sense that it has a dam.
既然是大河川 那当然也会有水坝了
Therefore, having dam curry here
所以有水坝咖喱饭
makes perfect sense!
也是天经地义的事
All right.
好
Let's have some dam curry!
那就吃水坝咖喱饭吧
And later, I'll try that Kawane tea soft serve...
然后 晚点再去吃小凛说的…
Guaranteed satisfaction.
绝对很好吃
...that Rin mentioned!
那个川根茶冰淇淋
JUMBO BUTAKUSHI (PORK SKEWERS)
(特大猪肉串)
SUPER YUMMY EXTRA LARGE BUTAKUSHI
(真的超级好吃特大猪肉串)
"BUTAKUSHI" A wild Butakushi has appeared!
(猪肉串) 突如其来的猪肉串
That'll be 400 yen.
总共400圆
Yum!
好好吃
I was completely lured in by that delectable aroma.
被香气迷得神魂颠倒 不小心就买了
The aroma of the Butakushi is deliberately pointed
居然刻意把猪肉串的香气 往在千头站下车的人那边吹
There's absolutely no escaping it.
这个绝对躲不掉啊
That Jumbo Butakushi was delicious.
特大猪肉串 甚是美味
But that's far from enough.
但是这样不够
I'm still not full yet.
余还没吃饱啊
Next up is the main course, dam curry.
接着是主餐 水坝咖喱饭
Let's dig in!
我要开动啦
Senzu's dam curry is modelled after
千头的水坝咖喱饭
the upstream Nagashima Dam.
是模仿上流的长岛水坝制成的
The fried shrimp represents the suspension bridges
炸虾是横跨水坝两侧的吊桥
while the boiled egg on the curry
而咖喱上的水煮蛋
symbolises the Okuoikojo Station.
则代表着奥大井湖上站
Rin and Aya are planning to ride all the way deep into Oigawa.
小凛她们好像要一路骑到 大井川深处去
I'll just get off at Okuoikojo Station.
我搭到湖上站就好
But the fun of dam curry doesn't stop there.
水坝咖喱饭的有趣之处可不仅如此
After admiring the presentation and tasting the flavours...
在欣赏完造型 并且品尝过味道后
Open the gate!
放水
One can even simulate the release of water from the dam.
还能模仿水坝放水
A dish with a playful touch is superb!
这种充满玩心的料理真棒呢
Fun to play and delicious to eat!
既有趣又好吃
I must learn well.
我也得好好学习
Dam curry is truly delicious!
水坝咖喱饭 甚是美味
"KAWANE TEA SOFT SERVE" And finally…
(川根茶冰淇淋) 然后 最后是…
Kawane tea soft serve for dessert!
饭后的川根茶冰淇淋
Thank you for the food!
我要开动啦
The aroma and bitterness of Kawane tea instantly fill in my mouth.
川根茶的香气和苦味 瞬间在嘴里扩散开来
The sweetness is just right. It tastes so refreshing.
甜度也控制得恰到好处 吃起来很清爽呢
So good!
真好吃
Oh, it's already so late.
居然这么晚了
The train has arrived.
电车已经来了
So, this is what I'll be riding.
要搭这个过去吗
It's so tiny and cute.
这台电车小小的好可爱
But that also means the interior is small and narrow.
不过因为很小台 车内空间也很狭窄
I'll sit here.
就坐这里吧
The conductor said this side offers a better view.
刚才站务员也说车门这一侧 比较能看到风景
We apologise for the wait.
抱歉让各位乘客久等了
The train bound for Ikawa is about to depart.
开往井川方向的列车即将出发
Wait!
等等…
We just barely made it!
幸好赶上了
You took too long choosing an ekiben.
都怪你一直在铁路便当那边 犹豫不决的
There were just too many options...
因为种类太多了嘛
Hello.
你好
And we're off.
出发了
Thank you for choosing this train.
感谢各位的搭乘
This train is bound for Ikawa.
本次列车开往井川方向
KAWABE FOODS
(川边食品)
NEXT EPISODE: JOURNEY TO HATANAGI AND THE ROAD TO HELL
(下集 前往畑薙 地狱的死亡之路)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)